John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Photographs, 1880 -- 1980; 1950 -- 1961; MS007.010; 0.5 Linear Feet; 127 Digital Object(s)
  - Portrait of John Holmes by Myron J. Files, 1969; MS007.010.DO.00272; Unknown (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Portrait of John Holmes by Charles J. Connick, 12/25/42, 1942; MS007.010.DO.00273; Unknown (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
- Personal and business records, 1927 -- 1998; 1927 -- 1962; MS007.011; 1.0 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  This series consists of publishing contracts, diplomas, and vitae. The bulk of the material dates from 1927 to 1962. The series includes the contract for the first work Holmes sold and publishing contracts for his books. Also included are Holmes' bachelor's degree and honorary doctorate from Tufts, and Holmes' draft cards from World War II.
  Additional material was added to the Holmes collection in June 2009 by Laura Cutter. An extensive amount of personal and business material was added to this series, much of it regarding the management of Holmes' works and estate after his death. It also includes personal materials relating to Holmes and his family, such as a sound recording from his birthday. Much of this material was added to box 059 - some was interfiled and some was housed in new folders. Also added to this series were condolence letters received by Doris Holmes after the death of John Holmes. This material is arranged alphabetically and was added to the end of the series in box 070.
  This series is arranged chronologically and alphabetically.
  - Personal and Business Records, MS007.011.059.00004; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 4)
  - Glueck Poetry Prize, 1960; MS007.011.059.00005; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 4)
  - Publishing contracts and permissions, 1964 -- 1987; MS007.011.059.00006 (Box MS007 Shared 4)
    Doris Holmes Eyges materials regarding the management of John Holmes' estate.
  - Permissions and correspondence for Anne Sexton biography, 1982 -- 1991; MS007.011.059.00007 (Box MS007 Shared 4)
  - Estate information (Tufts) and post-mortem, 1962 -- 1998; MS007.011.059.00008 (Box MS007 Shared 4)
  - Holmes' Robert Frost Collection [bibliography], 1962; MS007.011.059.00009 (Box MS007 Shared 4)
    Bibliography of John Holmes' collection of Robert Frost material, presumably inventoried after Holmes' death.
  - Holmes' Poetry Collection [bibliography], 1962; MS007.011.059.00010 (Box MS007 Shared 4)
    Bibliography of John Holmes' collection of poetry, presumably inventoried after Holmes' death.
  - Holmes' Diplomas, 1929 -- 1962; MS007.011.059.00011 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 5)
    John Holmes' diplomas for his B.A. (1929) and honorary degree (1962) from Tufts. Note that these items are stored in an oversize folder in the map case.
  - Doris, Evan, Margaret & John Holmes for his [John Holmes'] birthday [sound recording], 1959; MS007.011.059.00012 (Box MS007 Shared 1)
    Sound recording of/ during [?] John Holmes' birthday, January 6, 1959. Note that this item is housed in an oversize box with other John Holmes recordings. This item was added to the collection in June 2009.
  - Draft of a letter written by John Holmes announcing the birth of his son, Evan, MS007.011.059.00013; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 4)
    Added to collection in June 2009.
  - Life mask, 1927-01; MS007.011.062 (Box 62)
    Plaster life mask of Holmes, made by fellow Tufts student David Hertz, described in letter to Frances Randall, July 25, 1953.
  - Condolences, A, 1962; MS007.011.070.00001 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
    Added to collection in June 2009. Condolence letters written to Doris Holmes upon the death of her husband, John Holmes.
  - Condolences, B, 1962; MS007.011.070.00002 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, C, 1962; MS007.011.070.00003 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, D-F, 1962; MS007.011.070.00004 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, G-I, 1962; MS007.011.070.00005 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, J-L, 1962; MS007.011.070.00006 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, M, 1962; MS007.011.070.00007 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, N-P, 1962; MS007.011.070.00008 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, R, 1962; MS007.011.070.00009 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, S, 1962; MS007.011.070.00010 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, T, 1962; MS007.011.070.00011 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, U-V, 1962; MS007.011.070.00012 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, W, 1962; MS007.011.070.00013 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, X-Z, 1962; MS007.011.070.00014 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences, Unknown, 1962; MS007.011.070.00015 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Condolences from writers, 1962; MS007.011.070.00016 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
    Added to collection in June 2009. Condolence letters written to Doris Holmes upon the death of her husband, John Holmes. Letters from Helen Bevington, Morris Bishop, Phillip Booth, John Brinnin, Constance Carrier, John Ciardi, Richard Eberhart, David Ferry, Robert Francis, Donald Hall, Rolfe Humphries, Stanley Hyman, Jeremy Ingalls, Phyllis McGinley, Howard Nemerov, Howard Moss, Norman Pearson, May Sarton, Winfield Scott, William Jay Smith, Ted and Renee Weiss, and Richard and Charlee Wilbur.
- Robert Frost collection, 1925 -- 1962; MS007.012; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series consists of Holmes' collection of Robert Frost materials. Holmes was both a friend of Frost and an admirer of his work, and he actively collected materials relating to Frost's life and work. The dates of the collection material range from 1925 to 1962. The bulk of this collection consists of more than 70 books by Frost, containing work by Frost, or about Frost. Many of these are first editions, some of which are signed and inscribed. The collection also includes a nearly complete run of Frost's holiday cards, which were specially printed editions of his poems. Many of these cards are inscribed to John Holmes. There are several handwritten letters from Frost to Holmes with typewritten transcriptions made by Holmes, and several copies of Frost poems, including a handwritten version of Carpe Diem. Pamphlets and programs of Frost appearances attended by Holmes are also in the collection, including a seating list for Frost's 88th birthday celebration at the White House in 1962. Photographs and a bust of Frost round out the collection.
  A number of items were separated from the Frost collection, most of which were pieces added to the collection by unknown individuals after Holmes' death, or materials which are readily available from other sources. A list of these items follows:
  Copy of Senate Resolution 244 of the 81st Congress, 2nd session on Frost's 75th birthday
  Copy of Congressional Record of March 24, 1950 recording debate of Senate Resolution 244
  Letter from Senator Saltonstall to Holmes re Senate Resolution 244 (moved to MS007/005)
  Program from memorial service for Frost at First Parish, Watertown
  Copy of Atlantic Monthly, November 1957
  Copy of Harvard Alumni Bulletin, February 12, 1955
  Copy of Saturday Review, March 24, 1962
  Copy of Poetry Quarterly, Spring 1951
  Copy of essay reprinted from Dalhousie Review: "Robert Frost from his Green Mountain"
  Copy of Teaching and Learning Journal, 1960
  Clipping from NY Times, [1963] on Frost's 88th birthday
  Materials relating to the opening of the Frost Place in 1977: brochures and several letters
  Clipping of article about Frost "Wise Man"
  Clipping of review of book about Frost from Times Literary Supplement, February 1, 1963
  Clipping of Holmes review of "In the Clearing" in Christian Science Monitor, March 29, 1962 (moved to MS007/002)
  Program from memorial service for Frost at Amherst College February 17, 1963
  Copy of Yankee Magazine, November 1955
  Copy of Boston College Stylus, May 1957
  3 catalogs from the House of Books containing prices for Frost editions
  Copy of University Review, Winter 1968
  Copy of Informations and Documents [French] March 1, 1963
  Copy of Tuftonian, Winter 1957
  Copy of Town of Methuen Report 1965
  Copy of Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, March 1963
  Copy of Poetry, May 1913
  Associated Press ticker printout about Frost
  Bread Loaf Writers Conference Bulletin, April 1958
  Board of Overseers of Harvard College 1938: Official Ballot
  Unused copy of American Farms Engagement Calendar for 1947 containing Frost poem, Two tramps in mud-time, as the poem for April. Calendar was published by American Artists Group in New York.
  Copy of One More Brevity printed for Frost by the Wellesley College Book Arts Seminar for his birthday in 1957
  This series is arranged by type of material, then chronologically.
  - Frost Collection - Letters to Holmes, 1945; MS007.012.060.00001; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
    Frost, Robert
  - Frost Collection - Prose and Poetry, MS007.012.060.00002; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Material on Frost Bust, 1962; MS007.012.060.00003; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - White House seating chart, 1962; MS007.012.060.00004; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Event Programs, 1936 -- 1959; MS007.012.060.00005; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Pamphlet publications, 1936 -- 1959; MS007.012.060.00006; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Proofs of a Witness Tree, 1942; MS007.012.060.00007; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Christmas Cards, 1929 -- 1959; MS007.012.060.00008; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Christmas Cards, 1960 -- 1961; MS007.012.060.00009; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Frost bookplates, 1935; MS007.012.060.00010; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Frost Collection - Photographs, 1925 -- 1961; MS007.012.060.00011; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Holmes' Correspondence about Frost Collection, 1950 -- 1959; MS007.012.060.00012; Holmes, John (Box data_value_missing_017f0f6b806efe92050eb4f65866283e)
  - Robert Frost photograph, inscribed., 1955; MS007.012.060.00013 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 6)
    Inscribed "Robert Frost to his friend John Holmes wih affection, Jan 1955".
- Writings about Holmes, 1927 -- 1983; 1950 -- 1961; MS007.013; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series consists of reviews, articles, and memoirs of Holmes' life and work, and publicity materials about Holmes' books. The date of the material ranges from 1927 to 1983. The series also includes programs of which Holmes was a part, or which mention Holmes.
  Additional material was added to the Holmes collection in June 2009 by Laura Cutter. Articles, book reviews, and publicity materials were interfiled with original material in this series. Some material could not be interfiled and was added to the end of the series in box 070. The bulk of this material is posthumous writings about and tributes to John Holmes by various people and institutions. Also included are complete bibliographies of John Holmes' work.
  This series has no arrangement.
  - Articles and papers about Holmes' work, 1950 -- 1981; MS007.013.061.00001; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Memoirs about Holmes, 1933 -- 1980; MS007.013.061.00002; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Publicity materials for Holmes books, 1937 -- 1960; MS007.013.061.00003; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
    Includes publicity blurbs for "The Fortune Teller" by Mark van Dorin, Dudley Fitts, John Ciardi, Richard Eberhart, Richard Wilbur, Elizabeth Lawrence, and Robert Lowell.
  - Book reviews of Holmes' books, 1937; MS007.013.061.00004; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Programs including Holmes, 1927 -- 1969; MS007.013.061.00005; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Two journals with Holmes citations, 1964 -- 1971; MS007.013.070.00017 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
    Added to collection in June 2009. The Amherst Literary Magazine (Summer 1964) and Northwest Review (Summer 1971)
  - Tributes to Holmes, 1962 -- 1983; MS007.013.070.00018 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Tributes to Holmes: Tufts University, 1962 -- 1963; MS007.013.070.00019 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - Tributes to Holmes: Poetry in Crystal, 1963; MS007.013.070.00020 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - John Holmes Bibliography [of materials housed at Tufts], 1962; MS007.013.070.00021 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
  - John Holmes: A Bibliography, 1967; MS007.013.070.00022 (Box MS007 Shared 5)
    Added to collection in June 2009. Published in the Bulletin of the New York Public Library, May 1967.
- Family materials, 1813 -- 1976; MS007.014; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series consists of materials relating to the Holmes family. The materials range in date from 1813 to 1976. Series material includes a scrapbook compiled by Holmes' sister, who attended Jackson College and which contains Tufts memorabilia, as well as family records, and genealogical material. There is one bound volume which contains a typescript copy of Electa Nash's diary (1817-20) and reminiscences of other relatives. This series also includes a handwritten manuscript entitled "Reminiscences of [John Greanleaf] Whittier, by S. S. J." of unknown origin.
  - Family materials, 1813 -- 1976; MS007.014.061.00006; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Genealogy and Electa Nash's Diary, 1817 -- 1954; MS007.014.061.00007; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Writings by other members of Holmes' family, 1922 -- 1939; MS007.014.061.00008; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Reminiscences of Whittier, by SSJ, 1891; MS007.014.061.00009; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)
  - Scrapbook, MS007.014.061.00010; Holmes, John (Box MS007 Shared 6)